Due to this, our
у нас благодаря этому растёт своё
production is growing, we become more
производство мы становимся более
independent, so I don’t understand
самостоятельными так я Я плохо понимать
Russian, I understand America correctly
русский я правильно понять Америка
to make sanctions and Russia, because of the sanction, it
сделать санкции и Россия из-за санкции
is better to
лучше
develop,
развиваться да е
because
е Потому
I am a Russian year in the Russian community of
я я учить русский 2 год в русский община
California, I understand, if not quickly
Калифорния я понимать если не быстро
Speak if you say this
говорить вот если так говорить
can be clear in English, but
Понятно можешь отвечать на английском но
not all the words because I want to
не все слова потому что я хотеть
practice Russian, I go in a roulette,
практиковать русский я заходить рулетка
I teach Russian, I want to go to
я учить русский Я хотеть поехать в
Rusha my rush from Novosibirsk, in
Раша моя р Маша из Новосибирск она в
California, it teaches us Ran
Калифорнии Она учит нас Ran
you from which city
Вы из какой город
Volgograd is Volgograd
Волгоград Волгоград
this  This is
это это
where it is the
где это Это
south of
юг
Moscow Moskova
Москвы Москова
South of Moscow
Юг юг Москвы
at the bottom of Rostov Krasnodar,
внизу Ростов Краснодар
I don’t know
я плохо знать
GE this is a small
GE Это небольшой
city of Big Town or
город Большой Таун или
City it is a long long Large Lge
Сити Он длинный длинный large lge
oh you Students or
Ой вы Students или
work which professes
работаете какой профе
in
Я в
California
Калифорния
have a
иметь
collective farm agricultural farm
колхоз сельхоз сельхоз
It's Not
it's not
Village  I'm not a village,
Village у меня не не деревня
this is
это
Undertand it's collective farm collective farm - this is
understand It's No колхоз колхоз - это
when the
когда
general is your personality in the same farm Yes it's mes
общее это лично твоя ферма Yes It's M
is not a collective farm, but ey te Masha says
Yes это не колхоз а э My te Маша говорит
that a farm is a collective farm to
что ферма - это колхоз
clarify this word oh,
О я уточнить это слово Ой ну вы
what do you are not agronomist  Neo
какой и механики вы не агроном Нео
profiles we are reading a
проф проя мы чиним
tractor, we make a
трактора мы делаем
tractor, we create
трактора мы создаём
them to
их ты
develop a machine -builder
разрабатывать Машиностроитель
VRI
ври вместе
together, together this is one and the
вместе это одно и
same cars, I will make cars not
тоже машины я я буду делать машины не
only cars, but also large
только легковые Маленькие но и большие
tractors and what kind of tractors
трактора А какие трак
what tractors do you do and
ша я Какие тракторы вы делать ша или
combine which ranges which ranges  Tractor
комбайн какой ра трактор
Sh Rosselmash
ш россельмаш
Kirovets Belarus
Кировец Беларусь
I can’t hear such a tractor
Это я не слышать такой трактор
RO I heard, but I have not heard in our
ро я услышал но я не слышал у нас в
America such a tractor, they are not delivered by the
Америка такой трактор их не поставляют
internal
санкции внутренний
market not the
рынок не
USA large tractor,
США большой трактор
it is better
он лучше
to make a tractor worse and you are
хуже ты делать трактор и ты
not
не это
what you are after school  Yes, we
какой А ты после Школа да
create our own production technologies,
создаём свои технологии производства
that is, our production,
производства То есть у нас производство
thanks to these sanctions, has grown up
благодаря этим санкциям выросло выросло
the production, on the contrary, it was
производство у нас наоборот
better to understand the Russian sanctions
я правильно понять русский санкции лучше
to make Russia a
сделать Россия е
mustache, thanks to this,
раз ус благодаря у нас благодаря этому
our
растёт своё
production is growing more
производство мы становимся более
independent, so I become more independent  It’s bad to understand the
самостоятельными так я Я плохо понимать
Russian I correctly understand America
русский я правильно понять Америка
to make sanctions and Rosia from the sanctions
сделать санкции и росия изза санкции
better to
лучше
develop, to
развиваться Да
eat, do
есть пото
not be surprised, do not be surprised by
Не удивляйся Не удивляйся это
Russia and that you develop your iPhone
Россия и что вы разработать свой iPhone
your
свой
computer, we can create your own phone,
компьютер Мы можем создать свой телефон
but so far there is no need to
но пока в этом нет необходимости мы
use phones that are still as it were
пользуемся телефонами которые ещё как бы
We can supply China and live without it,
поставляет Китай мы можем и без этого
so
жить так
you are your phone
вы ваш телефон
american in Russian, this operating
American по-русски этот операционный
system is there is America can
система есть есть Америка может
turn off your
отключить вам
phones and but we will make our
телефоны да да Но мы сделаем свою
operating system we already have the
операционную систему у нас уже есть
Linux Linux operating system
Linux Linux
is an iPhone iPhone NOT RUS
Это iPhone iPhone мину не рус
RU IOONE  This is, in any case, no
ру ione это Это бай в любом случае No
linux no linux Baikal about SI Baikal Baikal,
Linux No Linux Байкал о си Байкал Байкал
I know Baikal - this is Lake
это я знаю Байкал - это озеро
Baikal, but also this is the operating
Байкал но также это и операционная
system of the Baikal operating system yes
система операционная система
yes yes, show me
Байкал Да да да Покажите показать мне
this operating system Baikal is
этот операционная система Байкал это
interesting he is still at the stage
интересно он он пока что на стадии
Developments and this is how to do the Baikal
разработки А это хотеть сделать Байкал е
do the eighth year and what
е делают делают восьмой год А что
Baikal BY means is not to buy
означает Байкал by - это покупать не
Nono Baikal - this is Lake Lake in honor of
ноно Байкал - это озеро озеро в честь
him the name of the operating
него назва операционную
system about Understand And what do you have the
систему о understand А что у вас после
details of your
сейчас детали свои
aircraft of the aircraft of the
самолёты самолёты
WAU Aircraft after the sanctions.  Aircraft you
Вау какой самолёт вы
do what kind of suns is an old
сделать какой су су су это старый
Soviet military aircraft, this is a
Советский военный самолёт Нет это новый
new new model
уже новая модель
of the Sovetic
дот й Советский
Samoy you have an analogue
самот У вас есть аналог
F35
f35
Politics is not a politician just what
политику не политику просто что делают
Russia does not love
Россия Твой друг не любить
America, I don’t like it when they talk
Америка Нет не любит когда разговаривают
about
о
politics, because there is no between politics, therefore  that it is
политике нету меж Ну потому что это
useless everyone will remain with his
бесполезно Каждый останется при своём
opinion so we are not talking about politics. We economy,
мнении Так мы не о политика мы экономи
we economy economics, he just did not understand the
мы экономика экономи Просто он не понял
initially what was the conversation, he just
изначально О чём шёл разговор он просто
left, and he went at that moment when we
уходил Ну и зашёл в тот момент когда Ну
washed, but
мыли но
not to talk so quickly,
говорить не так быстро
he left, we talked
повторить вот он ушёл мы разговаривали о
He returned about the economy and therefore I understood
экономике он вернулся и не так понял
therefore the negativity of
поэтому негатив
the Nega
Нега
and how much in Rush you now have the
А сколько у вас в Раша сейчас се
average salary, well, white salary
зарплата средняя Ну белая зарплата
how many
сколько
20,000 average salary in our city is
20.000 средняя зарплата в нашем городе
80,000
80.000
rubles 50
руб 50
somewhere well, 50-80,000 rubles mini
где-то ну 50-80 000 руб мини
this is 100 rubles
это это дор
is 100 rubles  This is 500,500 dollars
это 100 руб это 500 500 долларов
salary and 800
зарплата Да 800
how people work for $ 500 a
как люди работают за 500 долларов в
month you are deceiving me no, I am on the
месяц ты обманывает меня нет нет я я на
railway I
железной дороге
worked
работал
from 60,4,40 dollars 400
с 60 40 примерно 600 долларов 400
dollars
долларов
like in Russian without a house
как по-русски без дома
who lives
который который живёт
without a home without a certain
на без дома без дома без определённого
he receives places he receives from
места он получает он получает от
City $ 2000 a month
City 2000 долларов в месяц
pay $ 2,000
выплата у нас получа 2000 долла
and you work for
а у вас работать 500
$ 500, I do not joke it,
долларов я нете этого ты шутит
I don’t understand from Rasha so much
меня я не понимать откуда у Раша столько
money for a rocket if there is no money to pay
денег на ракета Если нет деньги платить
your people
свои люди
this rocket is money  salary no
э ракета есть деньга зарплата нет
money, we don’t have money and we have large
деньга Ну нет у нас есть и большие
salaries we have we said we said we said the
зарплаты у нас это мы сказали мы сказали
average salary is a small
среднюю зарплату Вот есть маленькая
average and
средняя и
big
большая больша
rubs even more often, so that
руб даже больше иной раз То есть как у
is, you have a large salary as
нас то есть у вас большая зарплата как у
our
нас
payment of homeless people help to find
выплата бездомный помогают найти
Work help us from us to
работу помогают рабо у нас у нас
receive $ 2,000 is 200,000 rubles from
получать 2000 долла это 200.000 руб у
you 50,000 rubles is a big salary how to
вас 50.000 руб Это большой зарплата как
get in Mle, that is, it says that 80,000 for
получать то есть говорит что 80.000 для
Russia does not receive 250,000 ru,
России нет в Америке получает 250.000 ру
but somehow, well, look at us in us
Ну как-то да Не ну смотрите У нас в
Russia is just a little lower than yours,
России просто цены чуть ниже чем у вас
therefore, based on this, such a
поэтому Исходя из этого Вот такая вот
salary is added up, you just
зарплата и складывается у вас буквально
have vegetables for rubles just
овощи стоят по руб просто
150 rubles 10 times less with us, we
у нас 150 руб в 10 раз меньше У нас
are literally vegetables, Kai
стоят буквально овощи Кай
Veles 56 rubles
ОВО 56 руб
costs you, well, it costs you, well, it costs
стоит у вас же он стоит
rub 20 kilograms of
Ну руб 20 долла килограмм
potatoes to you, I am trading, I am a
картошки к тебе сказать я я торговать я
farmer collective farm
фермер колхоз
I plant potatoes Batate is to sell
я садить картошка батат это продавать
potatoes. She wholesale when it
картошка она опт опт когда много
costs a lot of 70 kilograms
продавать стоит 70 цент килограмм
and retail is a dollar kilogram
а розница это в магазин доллар килограм
is 100 rubles for
это 100 рубль по
your 100 rubles is a lot of it is a lot of it is a lot of it is a lot and  you have
ваш 100 руб это много это много а у вас
how much 50 rubles per
сколько 50 руб
kilo watch watch watch this is
килограм смотреть смотреть это в два
twice as expensive potatoes
раза дороже картошка
for 1015 times more I
за 1015 раз больше в
understand Well you also have
понима Ну у вас ещё и налоги
big taxes you have
большие у вас налого оче
a lot of taxes you know how much we have this
много ты знать сколько у нас этот
percentage tax you say
процент нало ты говори
pain
боль
20 20% And
20 20% А
how much And how much  SKO and in
сколько А сколько ско и в
AG Farmers get
AG фермеры получают по
percent you get pruning by
процентам вы получаете обрезку по
percentage because you are a farmer
проценту получается потому что вы Фермер
pruning to do not
обрезка оче
halve you tax because
налог в два раза уменьшат Потому
it is not
что это не
reduced to increase it on the contrary
Уменьши это наоборот
and 7% tax for
увеличить А 7% налог у
all,
всех ну ну
well, we have a tax and
хорошо у нас налог
how much does it have a tax and how much does it have.  you are a mortgage percentage and 20
а сколько у вас ипотека процент А 20
is a family
это семейная
6%
6%
California 3% IMA We say it is a
California 3% имы мы говорить Это очень
lot of 3% ITA 20% if a person lives
много 3% ите 20% это если человек живёт
alone as you can pay
один Как как можно платить
20%
20%
mortgage 20% if a person lives one 6%
ипотека 20% если человек живёт один 6%
if a person has a family 6  % then
Если у человека Ну есть семья 6% тогда
he pays uh how much stop stop uh 20% -
он платит э ну сколько стоп стоп э 20% -
that's
это
uh you 4 years to a year you have to overpay
ээ ты 4 с по года ты переплачивать в два
twice for 30 years
раз 30 лет
I don't even understand what you're talking about
Я не пойму вообще чем вы разговариваете
a mortgage for 10 years is given maybe it can go up
ипотека на 10 лет даётся может и дойти
to 30
до 30
years
лет
30 30 years pay
30 30 лет платить
20  % you take out a mortgage for 30 years and
20% ты берёшь ипотеку на 30 лет и
it is slowly
потихоньку её
paid off by the bank in which you are
выплачивает от банка в котором ты
applying there is you You count how much
оформляю есть есть ты Ты считать сколько
you will pay at the end in total you
ты выплатить в конце суммарно ты
will pay five apartments for 30 years at
выплатить пять квартира за 30 лет по
20% Well, our real estate, our
20% Ну у нас недвижимость у нас
real estate is growing, our real estate
недвижимость растёт у нас недвижимость
is growing  for everything, real estate is now growing very quickly
растёт на всё сейчас очень быстро растёт
because the demographics of the
недвижимость потому что демография
country are increasing very quickly. On
страны очень быстро
the contrary,
повышается Наоборот
but no, on the contrary, they are
а нет наоборот
decreasing; our demographics are
она понижается демография у нас
decreasing, so our prices are rising
понижается поэтому цены у нас повышаются
like this. I understand you correctly that there
так Я правильно тебя понять что людей
are fewer people and prices for apartments are
становится меньше а цены на квартиры
higher, yes
больше да да
yes, if there are fewer people then  There are more empty apartments
так если людей меньше то квартир пустых
and the price should be
больше и цена должна быть
less don’t
меньше не
understand vo
понимать воо
if we
если у нас
have a City where people leave people less
есть Сити где люди уезжать люди меньше
uh real estate
ээ недвижимость
is cheaper if you have uh we have a City
дешевле если что у вас э у нас есть Сити
from which people leave and people become
из которых уезжать люди и люди стаёт
less empty the house is bigger and the price is less
меньше пустых дом больше и цена меньше
If  you people less where the price is
Если у вас люди меньше откуда цена
more well we have such an economy
больше ну у нас такая экономика
just yes the economy of Russia at the
просто да экономика России на данный
moment Well it’s so-so in general to
момент Ну она м так себе в общем-то
say And where can everyone run away
сказать А куда все убежать
where can everyone
куда все
run away oh there’s a
убежать ой очень
lot of nowhere to run away your
много не куда убежать твои
Friends by girls and Girls and
Friends по девочкам а Girls а
you A  I’m talking to you, increasing your
ты А я с вами разговариваю повышая ваш
interest in
интерес к
Russia, you sacrifice yourself for ra
России ты принести себя в жертва ра
Yes, it’s very interesting to communicate with me. I’m very
Да ми очень интересно общаться Я очень
respectable.
почтённого
She’s from Novosibirsk, this is sha about a beautiful
Она из Новосибирск это ша о красивый
city, a beautiful city, and Masha, Masha is
город красивый город и Маша Маша
beautiful, Masha is also beautiful, I’m very mother, I
красивый Маша тоже красивый Я очень мама
grew up there, my mother, My
росла там мама моя My
Mother, there  grew up when she was little
Mother там росла когда была маленькая
she went to hockey hockey mah
она ходила на хоккей хоккей ма
hockey Yes
хокей Yes
Inter her
Inter её
dad served in the
папа служил в
KGB your grandfather
КГБ твой дедушка
yes yes
да да
uh That is, your grandfather served in the KGB
ээ То есть твой дедушка служить в КГБ
so that you now sit in These walls in
чтобы ты сейчас сидеть в Эти стены в
this
этой
Russia Well, it’s like my choice is also
Раша Ну это как бы и мой выбор тоже
just
просто
a  where will I go? Well,
а куда я уеду Ну
I’m not, I’ll go wherever I want,
я не я уеду куда захочу это да
yes, but I’m studying here, I have a family here, I
Но я здесь учусь у меня здесь семья я
understand, I mean that your grandfather
понимать я имеет в виду что твой дед
is building a country where people have no
строит такой страна где люди не иметь
rights, no salary, and now his grandson
прав не иметь зарплата и сейчас его внук
lives in this
жить в это
country, a communist from
странах коммунист из
Yes, that's right, communism spoiled this
Да это верно коммунизм испортил эту
country very much beyond recognition
страну очень сильно до неузнаваемости во
during the Russian Empire, Russia
время Российской империи Россия
flourished, you knew, you know, when the
процветала вы знали вы знаете когда в
first car appeared in Russia,
России появился первый
when in fact, you don't
автомобиль когда на самом деле не
know 1886
знать 1886
Which
го Какой
factory It
завод Это
was Yakovlev
был Яковлев
and
и
meze, in my opinion meze, his
мезе по-моему мезе его
name was I'll check  in Google
звали я проверить в Google
sor
sor
Yakovlev and
Яковлев и
1896 this is well
1896 год это ну приме
primed So do you know what minut minut
дал Так а вы знае то что minut minut
minut you know when in London
minut ты знать когда в Лондон
metro metro yes
метро метро да
1 Well, well you 18
1 Ну ну ты 18
863 only when in London do the metro
863 только когда в Лондон сделать метро
Russia only in 33 years do assemble the
Раша только через 33 год сделать собрать
car You  understand the
автомобиль Ты понимать
difference, but trains already
разница но поезда уже в тот момент
existed in
существовали в
Russia at that moment, I tell you
России я тебе ещё
again, the Germans helped us build the
раз нам немцы помогали строить железную
railway, the Germans and the British built
дорогу немцы и
factories
ис заводы и фабрики
in the Russian Empire,
в Russian Empire строить
no. The British and the Germans did not
британцы нет Э англичане и немцы не
bring their railway equipment to us,
завозили к нам свою технику
they helped us,
железнодорожную заво они помогали нам
they helped  we build factories and
они помогали нам строить заводы и
introduced us to the
ознакомили нас железной
railway no. So, uh, these factories
дорогой нет Итак ээ эти заводы
belong to British companies,
принадлежат британские компании
if you look for example R ire the city of
если смотреть например R ire город
Donetsk, this is to create it John
Донецк это его создать Джон
Risch is an entrepreneur, he is to create a
Риш предприниматель он создать там
village there, he is to create technology gold
посёлок он создать техника золото
mining was also all ish and when the
добыча тоже было всё иш и когда прийти
communist Lenin comes they will take it away
коммунист Ленин они забрать это всё в
they destroyed everything in the state,
государство они всё разрушили
you knew
вы знали то
that, in my opinion, the king of Monaco announced a race
что по-моему король Монако объявил гонку
to his
до его
embankment for absolutely everyone,
набережной всем абсолютно всем первым
our man came first, I don’t remember
пришёл наш человек не помню
the name, the car was called Ruso Balt,
имя машина называлась Русо Балт
check the
проверьте
steering wheel is no longer there, it has sunk into oblivion like
рул уже нет она канула в лету как и
Nicholas II And this is when -  that was a bunch of years
Николай II А это когда-то был е кучу лет
ago
назад
Rusbal Now this car is
русбал Сейчас этой машины
gone. Can you gather some more friends of
нету А можешь можешь собрать ещё друз
yours Friends I want to
свои друзя Friends я хоте
say our
сказать нас
name is ma let's
зовут ма давай
sing we'll go now to the chicks I
пой мы сейчас тёлкам пойдём я хоте я
want to say about a minute I wanted to say an
хоте сказать о минута я хотел сказать
important message from American People
важное от American People сообщение
Let the guys
Пусть ребята
come up  and that friend with glasses is also glasses, so
подойти и тот друг в очки тоже очка так
I am a very important mess From uned Stat of
я хо очень важный mess From uned Stat of
amica to tell you
amica вам
clap your Russia
хлоп ваша росия
attacked
напала на
Ukraine Let
Украину Давайте
Putin Russia may ro escape to the independent
Путин росия мае ро спастись на незалеж
state Slava Ukraine
держави Слава украи
Come on it was simply divine I don’t
Давай це было просто божественно Я не
know who didn’t like this video  hto, do not flood
знаю хто не лайк Цей видео хто не залиши
the comment and not the skine of the VSM to your friends, you are
комент и не скине всм своим друзям вы
soulless of the person of the ex form of it is just a buzz and
бездушна особа це быв просто кайф и
the final girl
финалочка
just a yak stench
просто Як вони зараз
there is a dude with an American
там чувак с американцем
chame, let's like a squeal of a
ча нало российской Давайте лайк писка
letter on a telegram, a
комент пись на й Telegram прям зараз ось
lot
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
We, through the belt, is a firm bun and the bagato doughao, I
нас через скарг ОРВ твый бан и дуже
won’t show people to the people. I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about the streams about that for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that, for that, the operational calls
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
to write directly at the same time and the POP there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
the telegra of the OKM is
телегра окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
the information and the coronary information and the Podsyi is the trimati
информация и ми повинни з вами тримати
posty.  Operational calls are
постийний оперативный звязок
incompetent in that I have shown to you about the
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про Цей
YouTube glory to Ukraine sign
YouTube Слава Украине подпишись